in all points like as we are yet without sin.
And I was thinking about this as she was singing,
obviously Isaiah 53, it's not the message,
but oh, how it leads into the message so well this morning
as will be in the Gospel of Mark in chapter six.
But let me just read this to you.
I know she just sang about it,
but in Isaiah 53, the suffering savior,
it says he is despised in verse number three
and rejected of men, a man of sorrows
and acquainted with grief.
And we hid as it were our faces from him.
He was despised and we esteemed him not.
Surely he hath borne our griefs and carried our sorrows.
Yet we did esteem him stricken, smitten of God and afflicted
but he was wounded for our transgressions.
He was bruised for our iniquities.
The chastisement of our peace was upon him
and with his stripes we are healed.
All we like sheep have gone astray.
We have turned everyone to his own way
and the Lord hath laid on him the iniquity of us all.
In verse number 10, it says this,
yet it pleased the Lord to bruise him.
It's put him to grief when thou shalt make his soul
an offering for sin, he shall see a seed,
he shall prolong his days and the pleasure of the Lord
shall prosper in his hand.
I want you to notice it says this in verse number 11,
we see in verse 10, it talks about the death
and the resurrection but in verse number 11,
it says he shall see of the travail of his soul
and shall be satisfied.
The offering of the Lord Jesus Christ,
the substitutionary atonement that satisfied all the demands
for your salvation and for my salvation
and I am so thankful that we serve a risen savior.
The gospel of Mark chapter number six this morning,
Mark chapter number six and it's a familiar passage
of scripture, in fact here within the gospel of Mark
in this particular chapter, there's some amazing things
that God records for us, it's here in Mark chapter number six
the miracle of the feeding of the 5,000 is recorded by Mark
and it's the preceding text of scripture that we will study
verse 45 through verse 52 this morning
but the very preceding text of scripture
is the feeding of the 5,000.
Now this was a great miracle and we find that the disciples,
they thought it best to send the multitude of people away.
The day is far spent, send them away
but Jesus said give ye them to eat.
Now our God is always concerned about ministering
to the needs of people and we know that the greatest need
of humanity is that of redemption
and that's why he came to save the lost
and we find that he said give ye them to eat
and of course we understand as you study through
the miracle of the feeding of the 5,000
that the disciples had this idea, how are we gonna feed them?
We don't have enough, it's not sufficient
that all may have just a little bit
and Jesus took that which was given,
he blessed it, he multiplied it
and it's a very unique miracle because the disciples,
they were directly involved.
Not only were they eyewitnesses of this miracle,
they were the eyewitnesses of many miracles
but of the feeding of the 5,000, they participated.
They went to the Lord and they got the food
and they went to the people
and they distributed to the people
and then they went back to the Lord
and they got some more and they went and distributed
and so they were directly involved in this miracle
that is recorded in Mark chapter number six
and we find that after this miracle,
we find that the disciples, again,
having this personal involvement with this,
we come to verse number 45
and the feeding of the 5,000 is completed
and the Bible says in straight way,
so immediately after the feeding of the 5,000,
immediately after they gathered up the fragments,
remember, they took 12 baskets full,
this was more at the end than at the beginning
and we find that they were all filled,
they didn't just have a little bit,
they were all filled and straightway, immediately,
he constrained his disciples to get into the ship
and to go to the other side before unto Bethsaida
while he sent away the people.
So we find in verse number 45
that God provides for us kind of the backdrop
for all that's taking place
and so Jesus, the feeding of the 5,000,
this miracle is completed and what does he do?
Well, he goes to his disciples
and he tells them to get into a ship
and to go to the other side.
They're on the Sea of Galilee
and they're to go over to the other side.
We find also in verse number 45
that the Bible says while he sent away the people
and so the people were sent away,
the disciples were told to get into a ship
and to go to the other side
and we find that the Bible tells us in verse 46
and when he had sent them away,
he departed into a mountain to pray
and so we find that the Lord Jesus Christ
is there in a mountain and he's praying,
the disciples, they're told to get into a ship
and to go to the other side
and all the people that had just been partakers
of this wonderful miracle of the feeding of the 5,000,
they are sent away
and the Bible tells us this in verse number 47
and when even was come,
the ship was in the midst of the sea
and he alone on the land
and he saw them toiling and rowing
for the wind was contrary unto them
and about the fourth watch of the night,
he cometh unto them walking upon the sea
and would have passed by them
but when they saw him walking upon the sea,
they supposed it had been a spirit and cried out
for they all saw him and were troubled
and immediately he talked with them
and saith unto them, be of good cheer,
it is I, be not afraid.
Verse number 51, he went up unto them,
into the ship and the wind ceased
and they were sore amazed in themselves
beyond measure and wondered
for they considered not the miracle of the loaves
for their heart was hardened.
Before I get into the message this morning,
let me just make a comment about verse number 52.
You may see God do something miraculous
just as the disciples had experienced
and had participated in this miracle
in Mark chapter number six of the feeding of the 5,000
and you see God do what only God can do
and then straightway something else happens
and you forget all about what God had just done.
We're prone to forget, we're prone to wander
and we find that the Bible says
for they considered not the miracle of the loaves.
This was not something that had taken place
years or decades earlier.
This was something that literally moments earlier,
hours earlier in their life,
they were told give ye them to eat,
we don't have enough.
Lord, what do you want us to do?
The Bible tells us in Matthew
that he said this to them to prove them.
The Bible tells us he takes that little bit of sustenance
that's provided by that lad
and he multiplies it and he distributes it
and God works miraculously and hours,
I'm saying hours after this great miracle,
the Bible says that they considered not
the miracle of the loaves for their heart was hardened.
Listen, sometimes we can be just like the disciples,
we see God do something amazing,
we see God do something miraculous,
we see God do something that only God can do
and then we face another difficulty in life
and it's like we're gonna die.
Does anyone care?
Does anyone know?
You understand what I'm saying?
And we look at the passage of scripture
and I wanna draw, I've put it in the bulletin there for you
Holly did, I sent her the email and she does the rest
but it says in verse number 48
and I wanna draw your attention to these three words,
it's the title of the message this morning,
he saw them, he saw them.
We see that to begin verse number 48
and he saw them toiling and rowing.
We sang this morning to start our service
dwelling in Beulah land and one day
and I'm looking forward with great anticipation
of the day that I get to be
with the Lord Jesus Christ forever.
That this mortal shall put off immortality
or shall put on immortality
that this corruption shall put on incorruption
and we're gonna be changed in a moment,
what a blessing to be with him forever
and there'll be no more sorrow,
no more death, no more tears,
I mean it's gonna be glorious
and we sang about that to start the service this morning
and part of the chorus says
living underneath a cloudless sky
and the reality is that for some of us this morning
it might be a sky that's full of clouds.
That's the reality of life.
We can sing about and we ought to have joy
in the fact that one day
I'm gonna be with the Lord Jesus Christ forever
and there's gonna be no more pain,
no more sorrow, no more difficulties
but we live in this temporal world
and we may be facing a giant storm in our lives.
We may be dealing with as we sing that song
about a cloudless sky but we say man,
we're living under the clouds right now,
I mean it is the storm is absolutely raging
and that might be where you are this morning.
Can I tell you that God sees you?
That God knows where you are.
As we look at the text of scripture,
we find some very important things
and it's a very simple message this morning
but I hope that it'll be very encouraging
for each of us this morning.
I want you to find as you look here
at the text of scripture just three thoughts.
Number one, the Lord knows where you are.
The Lord knows where you are.
We find that again by way of introduction,
I've mentioned all that had transpired
to set the scene here of what's taking place
and we find that Jesus, the Bible tells us
in verse number 47, and when even was come,
the ship was in the midst of the sea
and he alone.
on the land. Jesus physically was not in the ship with the disciples. Jesus,
according to verse number 46, he departed unto a mountain to pray, and he's there
in that mountain. The Bible tells us at the end of verse number 47 that he alone
was the one on the land, and he's there. But notice where the disciples are. The
Bible says that when even was come, the ship was in the midst of the sea. Now, I
would submit to you this morning that they were exactly doing what they were
supposed to be doing. In verse number 45, the Bible says that Jesus constrained
his disciples to get into the ship and to go to the other side, before unto
Bethsaida. They were obedient. They were doing what the Lord Jesus Christ had
commanded them to do. Can I tell you that sometimes the storms come in your life
when you're obedient? I'm not talking this morning about storms that are the
result of your disobedience, though there are storms that are the result of
disobedience. Those aren't the kind of storms that I'm talking about this
morning. I'm talking about the storms that you're doing exactly what you're
supposed to be doing. You're obeying the Lord. You're following the instruction
that God has given, and you're in the midst of the storm, and we find that
Jesus is alone there on the land. He's praying. He's in the mountain, and the
Bible says in verse number 48, and he saw them. He knew exactly where they were. I
don't think as you look at the text of Scripture, when you begin to understand
what's taking place, and all that the disciples are doing, and how they're in
the midst of the sea, that they may not know exactly where the Lord is, but the
Lord knows exactly where they are. Amen? Now listen, there are times in which we
can see God's hand very evident at work in our lives, and we can see God's hand,
and we can see what God's doing, and physically for the disciples, they walked
with the Lord Jesus Christ, so there's many times physically that they could
see him. They couldn't see him at this moment, but he saw them. Sometimes you
might think, man, does, is God working? Is God doing anything? I don't see his hand.
It doesn't seem as evident. Does it ever happen in your life? You say, man, I'm in this
storm. I'm in this situation. I want to encourage you this morning that he sees
you. He says that he saw them. Notice over the book of Proverbs, if you will,
look at Proverbs chapter number five. In Proverbs chapter number five, we
understand this morning that we could speak about some of the attributes of
our God, and one of his attributes is that he is omnipresent. He is everywhere
present, and he, we understand he's omniscient, that he knows all things. He
has all wisdom, and we can rejoice. We ought to rejoice in the character, in the
nature, the attributes of our God. We see in Proverbs chapter five, in verse
number 21, the Bible says, for the ways of man are before the eyes of the Lord, and
he pondereth all his goings. God knows where you are. Now that's both comforting
and convicting. Amen? It's comforting to know that he knows us, and he knows where
we are, and he knows he sees us. It's also convicting to take that same truth, but I
want to look at it this morning from that comfort perspective, and we find
that it says he pondereth all his goings. In chapter 15, in verse number 3,
Proverbs 15, in verse number 3, the Bible says the eyes of the Lord are in every
place, beholding the evil and the good. When you think that no one knows where
you are, no one knows where you are, the Bible tells us that the Lord, he saw them.
Jeremiah would remind us of this truth, of the fact that our God is omnipresent,
and we can rejoice in understanding this morning that Jeremiah, he's living in a
very difficult time. He's been given a very challenging assignment to go to the
household of Judah to teach to them, to preach to them, and to call them to a
place of repentance, and understanding that the Babylonians, I mean, it's on the
eve of captivity and all that's going on, but God said, I'm gonna be with you. He
tells him that in chapter number 1, and we find that Jeremiah recognized that
though there's some times in which he was facing some great difficulties, that
God knew where he was, and God knows where you are. He knows where I am. He
knows. It says that he saw them, but I want you to notice that the text of
Scripture in Mark chapter number 6 doesn't only tell us, number one, that the
Lord knows where you are, but number two, the Lord knows what you are facing, what
you're facing. See, I'm glad to know that God knows where I am, but I'm also
thankful to know this morning that the Lord knows what I am facing. The Bible
tells us in verse number 48, and he saw them, then notice this phrase, toiling in
rowing. Toiling in rowing. I don't know if your mind works this way, but I don't
have a great imagination, but every once in a while I'll refer to it as a
sanctified imagination, and I try to look at this passage of Scripture and try to
see from the perspective of the Lord what he saw, and he's there in the
mountain, he's there for the purpose of praying, and he looks out over the Sea of
Galilee, and I've had the privilege to be at the Sea of Galilee. I've had the
privilege to be on a boat on the Sea of Galilee, and thankful there was no storm
on the day that I was on the boat that was on the Sea of Galilee, but I've been
there, and I've seen the mountains that surround that place, and I don't know
exactly where they were, and I don't know exactly where the Lord was, but we find
that as the Lord looked from those mountains, he saw exactly where they were,
but he saw exactly what they were facing. The Bible says they were toiling in
rowing. It kind of communicates to me the idea that all effort that they could
possibly humanly afford was put into rowing that boat and trying to get that
boat to safety. I mean, they're doing everything in their human power to get
that boat to shore, but the Bible says that they're toiling in rowing. Now, why
is it that they're toiling in rowing? For the Bible says this, for the wind was
contrary unto them. You ever feel like the wind is contrary unto you? I mean, you
just feel like it seems like you're trying to go in this direction, and
you're facing the headwind, and then you say, I'm gonna go this direction, and
there's a headwind coming from that direction. It just seems like the winds
are contrary, and here the Bible tells us again, if you would think about the
setting and understand what's taking place, and you would understand that the
disciples, they're told to go to the other side, so that's very simple when
you think about where they were, and where they were to end up, and they were
to cross over the Sea of Galilee. Now, many of these were familiar with the Sea
of Galilee. They were familiar with fishing, and boating, and all of that. It
was their livelihood, and they're familiar with storms that would rise up
in an instant on the Sea of Galilee, and they're there, and they know where
they're supposed to go, and they're heading in that direction, but the wind
is contrary. Let me ask you this morning, do you think that the Lord Jesus Christ,
God in flesh, knew when He told them to go to the other side, that they would
face a wind that was contrary? Absolutely. He knows everything. He knows everything.
That encourages me this morning. He knows what we're facing. He knows that they
were dealing with this. Now again, if you look at the text, and you understand
what's taking place, and you think about your life, and my life, and that in that
moment, while they're toiling and rowing, and while the storm is raging, and the
winds are contrary, and they're putting all of their human effort to get to
where they're supposed to go, I don't think that they're really wondering
where the Lord is. Sometimes you face difficulties in life. Sometimes you hear
somebody say something like this, how are you, and they say, well under the
circumstances. You ever hear somebody say that? What are they referencing? Well, all
the things that are going on, I mean, I'm kind of got my head above water, you know.
They might use that type of an expression, and the reality is that in
that moment, all of their focus and all of their effort was on what was taking
place right in front of them. But God saw them, and He knew what they were facing.
He knew exactly what they were dealing with. I want you to notice, it's very
interesting, as you look here, the Bible says in verse number 47, and when
even was come. Now, that's not a defined particular time. It's any time after
like 6 p.m., and so it could be various time with regard to that, but then it
says to us in verse number 48, and about the fourth watch of the night He cometh
unto them. Now, that's a defined period of time. That's between 3 a.m. and 6 a.m.
So what that reveals to me is that there's some time that passes when
they're toiling and rowing and facing a wind that is contrary, and God saw them,
but it's almost kind of that idea of God's gonna bring them to the end of
themselves. So you think about John 11. I love John chapter 11. It's a passage of
Scripture in which Jesus is informed about the sickness of Lazarus, and the
Bible tells us that He loved them. In fact, when the sisters send, Martha and
Mary send word to the Lord Jesus Christ about the sickness, they say, He whom thou
lovest is sick. I mean, what a way to be described, amen? He whom thou lovest is
sick, and yet we find that if you were to read John chapter 11, that Jesus did not
immediately go to where He was. In fact, we find that Lazarus would die before
Jesus would arrive. In fact, Martha would say He'd been dead for four days when
they arrived to the tomb.
But what was Jesus doing?
He was showing them that He had greater power than just being able to heal someone that
was sick, but able to raise somebody from the dead.
Amen?
And sometimes in those delays, it's difficult for us as the people of God.
We get in the storm, we get in the toiling and rowing, we get in the fact that the wind
is contrary, and it's hard for us, it's difficult for us, and we're facing all of
this, and we have these things that are taking place, and thoughts that are going through
our minds, and it's very challenging.
But we find that Jesus not only knew where they were, but He knew what they were facing.
Can I tell you this morning that there are some, and it's not an exhaustive list, but
there are some that are facing loneliness.
There are some that are facing heartache, and some that are overwhelmed, and some that
are confused, and some that deal with pressures and problems in life, some that are dealing
with troubles and uncertainty, and whatever it might be, and you know better than I,
God knows better than both of us, and He knows exactly what you're facing.
He knows the heartache that you have that maybe you can't even verbalize.
You've been in a position, you've faced a situation in life where you couldn't even
articulate how you're really feeling, what you're really facing.
But we find that the Lord knew exactly what they were facing.
He was familiar with it.
Now I would say this, as I've mentioned already, that our God is omniscient.
Our God is also eternal, and He knows exactly what we're facing this morning, and I would
say that it matters to Him because He loves us.
He loves us.
And what you're facing this morning, whether you think it's significant or whether you
think it's insignificant, whatever it is that you're facing this morning, God knows about it.
He's, listen, He became acquainted with grief that we might be acquainted with grace.
Isn't that awesome?
Again, I never even heard the song before, and Breonna sang that song this morning, and
how well it goes with the message, listen, our God knows what we're facing, and it matters
to Him because He loves us.
And you might come to the place where you say, nobody understands.
No, listen, God does.
Nobody cares.
No, God does.
Casting how many of your cares?
Casting all your care upon Him.
Why?
For He careth for you.
Casting thy burden upon the Lord, why?
We find that in Psalm 55 because He will, the promise that He will sustain thee.
Praise God.
Let's go over in Psalm 139, if you will, Psalm 139, and I want you to notice what the
psalmist says here, and Psalm 139 is an important passage of scripture that often we reference
and we should, rightfully so, to deal with the sanctity of life and how precious life
is, and we understand that life begins at conception, and we're thankful for the gift
of life and the blessings that God has given us, and we see that truth in Psalm 139.
We also are reminded, as the psalmist ends this psalm, about the importance of saying
to the Lord, search me, O God, and having that time of personal, just dealing with the
Lord in that personal time of allowing the Lord to search us.
We find that the psalm begins this way, in Psalm 139 in verse number one, O Lord, thou
hast searched me and known me.
And I encourage you this morning that He knows you.
He knows.
You say, nobody else knows.
God does.
I've not told anyone.
God knows anyway.
God knows.
He knows exactly what we're facing this morning.
As far as we can tell from the text of scripture, now listen, in Mark chapter number six, and
we understand there's passages that you can go to and you can read where people in distress
call out to the Lord for help.
But as far as we can tell from the record of Mark chapter number six, they're toiling
and rolling because the winds are contrary and there's no reference that they're crying
out for help.
But God knew.
Because He knows.
He knows where we are and He knows what we're facing.
Notice in verse number two of Psalm 139, thou knowest my down sitting and mine uprising.
Thou understandest my thought.
Notice it says afar off.
Thou compassest my path and my lying down and art acquainted with all my ways.
This morning, I want you to take comfort.
I want you to be encouraged this morning that God knows where you are.
That God knows what you're facing.
But I want you to think about it as we come to the third thought this morning from this
portion of scripture.
Not only does God know where you are, know what you're facing, but the Lord, number three,
He knows what you need.
The Lord knows what you need.
Can I tell you this morning that what you need may be different than what you think
you need.
God knows exactly what our needs are.
And can I encourage you this morning that He alone can meet the need.
He alone can meet the need of every single person in this building this morning.
Any person that's watching online this morning.
Any person that would go back and listen to this message at some later date on some YouTube
or wherever it might be.
Any person that's dealing with any difficulty at that moment.
Whatever the need is, God alone can meet that need.
That encourages me.
That causes me to rejoice greatly.
I cannot, humanly, I cannot meet the needs of those that are present here this morning.
I can't.
There's needs that we humanly just cannot take care of.
But God can.
God can.
Can I encourage you with this?
Not only can He, He wants to.
He wants to.
He wants to provide for you.
He wants to give you exactly what you need this morning.
Notice with me, as you look here in Mark chapter number six, the passage records for
us about what's transpiring and how that they were toiling and rowing and the wind was contrary
unto them.
And it tells us the timing about the fourth watch of the night.
He cometh unto them, walking upon the sea and would have passed by them.
Now I'm going to pause here just for a moment.
We're not going to turn to the other portions of scripture.
But in Matthew chapter number 14, this same event is recorded.
In Matthew chapter number 14, and it's in that portion of scripture that God tells us
about Peter walking on the water.
And you can read of that.
You can go back and look at that account.
And it's very interesting because each of the three accounts of this miracle that we're
looking at here this morning of this event, there's slightly different things that are
given to us about it from each of the writers of the gospels.
And we find that in Matthew 14, it tells us that Peter was walking on the water.
Now remember, they're fearful.
They're in the midst of the storm, all the things that are taking place.
And there in Matthew 14, Peter says, Lord, if it's thou, bid me come to thee.
And so he says, come.
And what does Peter do?
Well, Peter walks on the water.
Now don't miss that because oftentimes we say, yeah, but he sank.
Yeah, but he walked on water and he had more faith than anybody else that was in the boat
to even ask the question.
Amen.
No one else, none of those other disciples said, Lord, if it's thou, bid me come to thee.
But Peter did.
And he had enough sense when he began to sink to say, Lord, save me.
Amen.
And Jesus did.
And he walked back to the boat and we find that the record is there in Matthew 14.
Notice this as we look here at the text of Scripture in Mark chapter number six, it says
that he would have passed by them.
Now it's very interesting when you consider that thought in verse number 48 and as you
really try to meditate upon that and try to figure that out, why does it say that he
would have passed by them?
Pastor, you just told us that God loves us and that he knows where we are and he knows
what we're facing and that he's able to meet our needs because he knows what we need.
And you said these things, but the text says that he would have passed by them.
Can I tell you this this morning?
God doesn't force himself upon anyone.
God will let you continue to toil and rowing if that's what you want to do.
Amen?
I'm going to do it my way.
The Lord's not going to force it.
He's not going to force it.
You know a great truth that we find in John's gospel?
In John chapter number six, again this event is recorded there, and here's a phrase that
God gives us in John chapter number six.
It says that they willingly received him into the ship.
Can I tell you that made all the difference for them?
And they willingly received him into the ship because he would have passed by them.
He's not going to force himself upon you.
He didn't force you to get saved.
Amen?
Right there.
Right?
He didn't force you to get saved.
It was part of the song also that Brianna sang there in John chapter number one.
He came to his own.
His own received him not, but as many as received him, to them gave he power to become the sons
of God.
For whosoever shall call upon the name of the Lord shall be saved.
He offered to you.
He paid for your sin.
He offers to you the free gift of eternal life, but he doesn't force you to be saved.
He doesn't force you to grow.
He doesn't force you to be in church this morning.
He didn't force you to read your Bible.
He doesn't force you to pray.
He doesn't force you to receive his help, but he wants to offer it.
He's a very present help in the time of trouble.
We read that in Psalm 46, and now remember the Bible says that he came to them in verse
number 48, and he would have passed by them.
So he came to them in verse number 48, and he would have passed by them.
He would have passed by them.
where they were. He is a very present help in the time of trouble, but you gotta receive
his help. Amen. Sometimes we just try to figure it out ourselves. Listen, think about little
temporal things in life that you struggle with. And you're struggling to do something
and somebody else is right there that could possibly provide you with help and you're
just gonna struggle through it on your own. Instead of just letting somebody else help
you. Whether it's pride or stubbornness or whatever it might be, I don't know. We'd all
have to answer the question for ourselves, but there's somebody there that's available
to help and you don't take their help. You're not willing to receive their help. Listen,
the Lord Jesus Christ is a very present help in the time of trouble. He's not only able
but he's available. And we find here this morning that it says that he would have passed
by them. So he knows what we need. Notice with me in verse number 49 of the text it
says, but when they saw him walking on the sea they supposed it had been a spirit and
cried out. Verse 50, for they all saw him and were troubled and immediately he talked
with them. Can I tell you? This is precious to me. The Bible tells us that he talked with
them and noticed these words and saith unto them. You know what we need? We need a word
from God. We need a word from God. I'm so thankful for God's word this morning. I'm
so thankful that God's word is profitable. I'm so thankful this morning that the entrance
of thy words giveth light. I'm thankful this morning that his word gives comfort and it
gives the strength that we need. And we find that what they needed in that moment, they
needed a word from God. Now notice the word that he gives them. In verse number 50 the
Bible says, be of good cheer, it is I, be not afraid. Now as best I can understand hermeneutically
as you study this portion of scripture, the storm is still raging. Okay? As best I can
tell, you can look at the Greek, you can do whatever you want to do, as best you can tell
the storm is still raging. Why? Because the Bible tells us that they saw him, they were
troubled, he talked with them. Listen, he's not in the boat yet. Alright, we're going
to see it in just a moment when he comes onto the ship, but he's not there. And notice
he said to them, it says that he talked with them and saith unto them, listen this morning,
we need a word from God. We need a word from God. And he says, be of good cheer, it is
I, be not afraid. In the midst of the storm, when you're toiling and rowing, when you're
dealing with all the wind that is contrary, at that moment Jesus says, be of good cheer.
Really? Do you not see what we're facing? No, no, he's here and he's giving you a word.
It is I, be not afraid. Listen, the truth of Hebrews chapter 13 when we talk about that
and often we reference the truth that he says that I'll never leave thee nor forsake thee,
but the wonderful truth of the promise is this, in verse number 5, let your conversation
be without covetousness and be content with such things as you have, for he hath said
I will never leave thee nor forsake thee, so that we may boldly say, the Lord is my
helper, notice, and I will not fear what man shall do unto me. I would say to you, I will
not fear what the storm could do unto me as we look in Mark chapter number 6. And Jesus,
he gives them a word. Why do I make such emphasis on this? Because God's word is precious
and it's available to us and I want you to know this morning that God will give you truth
from his word that will meet your need. Whatever that need is, his word, Jesus is the answer.
His word is the answer. And we find that as we spend time with God regularly in his word,
as we have that privilege of being able to have a complete Bible and reading it and then
assembling like we are today and hearing it preached, that God will take his word and
he'll speak to us through his word. And I'm so thankful this morning that God does that.
That when you read your Bible this week, as you have the opportunity to read the scriptures
that God will speak to you through his word. God will meet your need. I often will use
a phraseology of filling the well. You know, when a well is empty, that's no good. Amen?
If you've ever had a well and you have the well water, if that well is empty, they talked
about priming the well and kind of the process for that. But if the well is empty, you've
got problems if the well is dry. We need to keep feasting on the manna from heaven and
keep feasting on the word of God so that we continue to fill the well, so to speak. Why?
So that in the moment of the storm, God can take that word that we've read and he'll minister
to us. Because the Holy Spirit will remind us. He will guide us in all truth. He will
teach us the scriptures and we have the privilege this morning of having the Bible. And here
the Bible tells us in Mark chapter number 6 that he talked with them and saith unto
them. When's the last time that you could say God spoke to me? I'm not talking about
audibly. I understand all of that with regard to the fact that the canon is closed and so
on and so forth. But I'm saying that you actually got alone with God. You were reading his word
and it wasn't just some type of rote religion. It wasn't just some type of check in a box
that I did my Bible reading today. But I'm saying that you got alone with God and God
spoke to you. That God gave you something from his word. That God met a need in your
heart. Why? Because he uses his word. If I ask you that question this morning and you're
like I can't remember the last time, you need revival. You need to get a word from God.
I'm not saying that in a condescending way. I'm trying to encourage you this morning that
God wants to meet your need. Listen, there are things that we listen to, there are things
that we watch, we hear so many things today. There are people that are listening to podcasts
all the time and hours upon hours of news and media and podcasts and so on and so forth
and then they spend five minutes, if that, in God's word. But truly it's the word of
God that will meet your need. Jesus is the living word of God and he's given to us the
written word of God and he wants to give you a word this morning. And we find that it tells
us in verse number 50 that he saith unto them, but then notice in verse number 51 how precious
is this. It says this in verse 51, and he went up unto them into the ship. Aren't you
thankful that you can have fellowship with God? You can enter into his presence. We find
that the Bible tells us in thy presence is fullness of joy. We find that in the book
of James as we think about the truth and considering the fact that he says draw nigh to God and
he will draw nigh to you. And we find here that the Bible says that he went up unto them
into the ship. They could not go to where he was, but he came to them. Think about that.
Think about that. They're in the midst of the sea. He's on the mountain alone praying.
They're toiling and rowing. I don't think they know exactly where he is, but he knows
exactly where they are. They cannot physically go to where he is, so he came to where they
were. Think about it this morning. Rejoice this morning in knowing that we have a God
who loves us, that we have a God who knows where we are and he knows what we're facing
and he knows what we need this morning. And he knows this morning the greatest need, I
mentioned it earlier, of humanity is redemption. And maybe this morning there's someone here,
someone that's tuned in via live stream, and you've never trusted Jesus Christ as your
personal Savior. Today is the day of salvation. That is the greatest need of humanity, that
you'd be saved by the grace of God. And can I tell you that only Jesus can meet that need.
For by grace are you saved through faith. And that not of yourselves, it is the gift
of God, not of works, lest any man should boast. And we find that the greatest need
of humanity is to be saved by the grace of God. And he alone can meet that need. He is
the Savior of the world. And he wants to be your Savior this morning. But can I tell you
for the people of God this morning, though your greatest need of salvation may be met,
you're here this morning and you have needs. I went through the list and I said that it
wasn't exhaustive of some things that we can face in life and the trials and the storms
and the troubles. And some of yesteryear have made the statement that you're either in the
midst of a storm, you've just come through a storm, or there's a storm on the horizon.
And for many of us in the Christian life, we can understand that, we can relate to that.
Can I tell you that sometimes the storms come up in just a moment. You didn't think it was
coming. You didn't anticipate it. And man, it's just upon you. You thought, man, I didn't
know this was coming. I didn't see this coming. Yes, but God knew about it. And I don't know
this morning of what your need is, but I know that God is able to meet the need. And I know
this morning, listen, if you need instruction, God will provide instruction. If you need
direction in your life, you don't know where to go, God will provide direction.
to go or where to turn and you're seeking the Lord,
He's able to give you the direction that you need.
If you're overwhelmed, the Bible says that
when I'm overwhelmed, lead me to the rock
that is higher than I.
Listen, He knows the sorrows of our hearts.
He knows our needs.
I mentioned already in Psalm 46, in verse number one,
that the Bible says that our God is a very present help
in the time of trouble.
Now, Psalm 46 is a familiar psalm for a few reasons.
One is verse number one.
Another one that's probably the most common known reason
that Psalm 46 is popular is because of the first statement
in verse number 10, be still and know that I am God.
But I want you to understand that that's more than
just some kind of plaque on a wall in a house.
He is God and we are to be still and to know that He's God.
But notice what the text tells us in Psalm 46.
The Bible says God is our refuge and strength.
Listen, if you need some kind of strength this morning,
whether it's physical strength or spiritual strength
or emotional strength, whatever it might be,
He is our strength.
And we find that it says that He's a very present help
in trouble, therefore.
Now, the therefore, I know preachers of yesteryear
used to say it all the time and it's so easy
for us to understand.
When you see therefore, you find out what it's there for.
Because I understand three very important things.
Number one, that God is my refuge.
Number two, that God is my strength.
And number three, that He is a very present help
in trouble because I understand and acknowledge
those three foundational truths.
The Bible says, therefore, will not we fear?
What did God, what did Jesus say to him
when He gave him the word?
He said, be of good cheer.
It is I, be not afraid.
In Mark chapter number six, that was the word
that Jesus gave them in verse number 50.
And we find here it says, therefore, will not we fear?
And then notice the things that are mentioned
in verse two and three.
I mean, these are catastrophic events.
And He says, though the earth be removed
and though the mountains be carried
into the midst of the sea,
though the waters thereof roar and be troubled,
though the mountains shake with the swelling thereof,
Selah, meditate, think about this.
Listen, He is our refuge, He is our strength,
He is a very present help in the time of trouble.
And He wants to meet your need this morning.
And I don't even know, you say, pastor,
you don't know my need.
Can I tell you something?
And I don't say this because I'm not compassionate.
I don't really need to know your need.
Now, it's okay if I do know what your need is
and if I counsel you and give you direction
and try to point you to the Lord.
But listen, any of you that ever sat in my office
for counsel, here's what I do.
I'm not pointing you to me.
I can't help you.
I try to point you to God.
Let's take the Bible.
Let's try to help you understand
here's what the word of God says.
Some of you sat in my office for marriage counseling.
I can't help your marriage, but God can.
Some of you sat in my office because you got kid problems.
I can't help your kids, but God can.
Amen?
And you go on and on and on.
Financial, whatever it might be.
I'm not a financial guy, but there are some Bible principles
that God gives us that I could try to point you to
and try to help you.
Why?
Because he can meet your needs.
So here's what the psalmist says to wrap it all up
in Psalm 121.
You don't even need to turn there.
But the Bible says, I will lift up mine eyes to the hills.
Now think about it just for a moment.
Where the disciples are, where Jesus was,
he's in a mountain, he's praying.
He saw them, he knew where they were,
knew what they were facing, knew what they needed.
Sometimes we're so much in the midst of the sea,
and yes, we read this portion of scripture and we rejoice.
Man, listen, this was recorded for us,
but listen, it's recorded for us
so that we could be helped in our storm.
My storm's different than your storm,
and all of our storms are different than the storm
that they faced on the Sea of Galilee that day.
Why?
Because we're not in a boat going across the sea.
We're facing storms.
I will lift up mine eyes into the hills.
From whence cometh my help?
My help cometh from the Lord, which made heaven and earth.
He's the creator God.
Let there be light.
There was light.
He spoke it all into existence,
and he's your helper, and he's my helper.
For those disciples, toiling and rowing,
the wind was contrary.
They were just obeying what Jesus said,
and they find themselves facing a great storm,
and Jesus saw them.
He saw them, and he knew what they were facing,
that they were toiling and rowing.
The winds were contrary, and he talked with them,
and he spake unto them.
He gave them a word, and then it says that he went up
unto them, in verse number 51.
Praise God for the fellowship.
Abide in him.
We can have that fellowship.
He wants to meet your need this morning.
I don't know what it is.
I don't know what heartache you're carrying this morning,
but I know that Jesus cares,
and I know that he's able to give you
exactly what you need.
He said to Paul, my grace is sufficient for thee.
That wasn't just a promise to Paul.
That's a promise to each one of us.
Remember that we're to come boldly
unto the throne of grace, that we may obtain mercy,
and find grace to help in time of need.
I don't know what your need is in this time,
but I know the one that can meet the need,
and I wanted to point you to Jesus this morning,
and I wanna encourage you this morning
that he knows where you are, he knows what you're facing,
and he knows what you need.
Let's pray.
Father, we love you.
We thank you for loving us.
We thank you for the word of God.
Thank you for this portion of scripture,
this passage, this record that you've given us
of this event in the life of the disciples.
As we think about this particular event,
we're reminded of our own lives.
God, in a crowd of any size,
there's needs that are represented by people, real needs.
Some greater than others, but all needs.
Maybe somebody needs to be saved this morning.
They've never trusted Jesus as their personal savior.
I pray that in just a moment, they'd come to this altar,
and we'd have an opportunity to take a Bible
and show them how they could know for sure
that heaven is their home.
The list of needs is beyond my ability to exhaust,
but I'm grateful to know that you as our lovingly,
omniscient, compassionate God,
that you know the needs of those that are here this morning.
And God, I pray that in the moment
that you'd move and work and help these folks,
Lord, to do as the psalmist said in Psalm 121,
to lift their eyes into the hills
from whence cometh their help.
Lord, help us to trust you and to hear from you
and to apply the truth, that we'd receive the help,
that we would not let you just pass on by,
but that we'd willingly receive what you have for us.
God, you'd help us as only you can.
I pray that you'd be honored and glorified
for it's in Christ's name we pray.
Would you stand with me?
Heads are bowed, eyes are closed,
and just a moment, Kimberly's gonna play on the piano,
and as she does, the altar will be open,
and I wanna encourage you this morning,
if you're not sure of heaven,
today is the day of salvation.
Mark is here if you're a man,
and Brianna's here if you're a lady.
Take a Bible, show you, you can know for sure
that heaven is your home.
Many of you, I know personally,
I've heard your testimony as a salvation.
I know you're saved.
Maybe you came in here this morning with some needs,
some heartache.
Maybe you just need to come to this altar
and get alone with the Lord,
and get the help that only God can provide you with.
As Kimberly plays, the altar is open.